Ruth Morais

Project Implementation Specialist

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

History of developing successful sales process improvement and marketing initiatives, designed to increase revenue. Strong background in sales and marketing project management.

Superior relationship-building skills and experience working collaboratively with customers, vendors and sales team.

Senior Sales Specialist

Cardinal Health Glastonbury, CT 8/2016-Present

- Played a key role in decreasing turnaround time on pricing proposals from 8-10 days to 3-4 days
- Conducting product research for sourcing, technical information
- Developing proposal unit process and procedure training guides for internal customers and new hires
- Maintaining the electronic library with information for proposals, sample graphics and photos

Sales and Training Development Facilitator

BBN Glastonbury, CT 7/2014 - 8/2016

- Drove growth by focusing on customer service, customer education on customized solutions for increased sales, and teamwork
- Developed client facing product training programs, including oversight of the company-wiki, FAQs, manuals and videos
- Worked with SME's and management to develop and implement strategic projects (i.e. CRM), and new product development (i.e. .bank loan portal) with quantifiable metrics
- Maintained intranet and website content as directed by Marketing
- Reported customer behavior, competency gaps, and product trend analysis

Event Coordination Assistant

Davis Communications • Windsor, CT • 5/2012-7/2014

- Worked with Logistics teams to successfully execute all event action plans
- Planned collateral preparations, arranged venue accommodations and attendee lists
- Provided the a primary level of sponsor assistance and access control

Sales & Marketing Support

Westbrook Technologies Inc. • Branford, CT • 6/2012 - 8/2013

- Managed the data migration and implementation of MS Dynamics CRM
- Created sales proposals pricing, RFP responses, and pricing agreements
- Produced weekly and monthly sales reports for the CEO and sales team

860.833.5289 ariasmorais@gmail.com East Hartford, CT/Willing to travel

SKILLS

Business Process Improvement
Salesforce, MS Dynamics CRM
Customer Training Development
WebEX, GoToMeeting, Skype
Vendor Relations and Negotiation
Camtasia, Snaglt, Geenio
Project Coordination
Slack
Basecamp

MS Dynamics GP (Accounting Software)
MS Office Suite

HIGHLIGHTS

Worked on Logistic team for the Documentary premiere of 1984 Olympic Silver Medal Winner Nelson

Managed training programs for 160 customers

Recognized for Training Plan and Company CRM Implementation

Developed first-of-its kind sales dashboard, customer and product trend analysis

Played a key role in company's initiatives to increase employee involvement and morale

EDUCATION

(Incomplete)
Bachelor of Arts, of Business
Albertus Magnus, New Haven, CT